&gt;&gt; Okay, we are here in the Google Self-Driving Car.
OK！ 私達は今Googleの自動運転車に乗っています。
It's obviously driving itself.
言うまでもありませんが自動運転です。
And it's doing everything by itself.
この自動車は完全に自動です。
&gt;&gt; And I am here as a passenger.
そして私は乗客としてここに乗っています。
I'm really hoping that Sebastian did a good job in training this,
Sebastianがこの車を良く学習させていることを願ってます。
because he is not driving right now, and I-
なぜなら彼は今、運転をしていないからです。
&gt;&gt; I am not driving, it drives better than me.
私は運転していませんが、自動車は私より運転が上手いですね。
&gt;&gt; I am at the mercy of this car.
私の命は今、自動車に託されています。
&gt;&gt; So why are we talking about self-driving cars then?
それでなぜ私たちは自動運転車の話をしているのしょうか。
&gt;&gt; Why are we talking about self driving cars?
なぜ私たちは自動運転車の話をしているの？
Well we're going to start by talking about supervised classification, and
"supervised classification"の話をしょうとしているのかしら
self-driving cars are one big supervised classification problem.
自動運転車は"supervised classification"の大きな事例ですから。
&gt;&gt; What does supervised mean?
"supervised classification"を説明できる？
&gt;&gt; Supervised means that you have a bunch of examples,
"supervised" は「監督された正解の事例の集まり」という意味です。
where you know sort of the correct answer in those examples.
多くの事例を監督して、正解の事例だけを集めます。
So I know that you have an example of this from the self-driving cars.
私はあなたが自動運転車から行動事例を収集したことを知っています。
&gt;&gt; Yeah so I mean we train our car and
そう。つまり私は自動車を訓練して、
we show the car what's the right behavior.
自動車に「正解の行動事例とは何か」を教えたのです。
And we did the DARPA Grand Challenge we would take it out for a spin and it would
高速道路でスピンした車があった場合、人間ならどう運転するか
very carefully watch us human drivers drive and would emulate our behavior.
自動運転車は注意深く観察し、人間の運転を真似します。
&gt;&gt; And in fact, this is sort of how people learn to drive, right?
実際、それは人間が運転を学ぶのと同じですね。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I think so. When I was a child, I watched my parents drive.
そうだと思います。 私も子供の頃両親の運転を見て運転を学びました。
And they weren't really good drivers, but
両親は最高の運転手ではありませんでしたが、
I would still copy a lot of stuff from them.
それでも私が学ぶべきことはたくさんありました。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so it's kind of like,
なるほど、それでは似ていますね
in the way the humans drive by watching lots of examples.
人間のドライバーが多くを経験して運転できるようになることと。
That's what computers do when they're doing machine learnings.
コンピュータが機械学習を行う時、
You give them lots of examples, and they start to figure out what's going on.
あなたは多くの事例をコンピュータに与え、その意味を理解させねばなりません。
That's what we'll be learning about.
それがこのレッスンで学ぼうとしていることです。
&gt;&gt; And it's totally true.
その通り。
In this unit, you're going to be learning about
このレッスンでは機械学習を学びます。
machine learning, the same way we program self-driving car.
私たちが自動車を学習させたのと同じ方法で
You're going to program data and
データをプログラミングして
test out whether you can make a car go fast and slow at the appropriate time.
自動車が適切なタイミングで加速、減速できるかをテストします。
using machine learning supervised learning.
使うのは機械学習の"supervised learning"です。
&gt;&gt; That's right. So
そうですね。
we're going to be looking at a really cool terrain classification problem that
私たちは今、地形の分類というとても難しい問題に取り組んでいます。
was very important for Stanley.
これは整備されていない場所での運転において、重要な問題です。
You want to introduce that?
詳しく説明してくれる？
&gt;&gt; So, in Stanley's case, I was driving through the desert and
整備されていない場所の一つ、砂漠を運転していた時のことです。
the desert terrain is like ruts
砂漠の地形は轍だらけのように見えて、
So it you drive too fast, you are running the risk of flipping over and
そのため自動運転でスピードを出しすぎて横転し、
destroying yourself.
自損事故を起こすリスクがありました。
So one thing we've trained the car to do is to really slow down at
そこで自動車を学習させ、適切なタイミングで
We did this not by writing little rules,
ちょこっとルールを追加するのではなく、
we did it by us demonstrating to the car how we drive.
私たち人間がどのように運転をするか、自動車に見せてあげたのです。
And it will just emulate us.
その結果、自動車は我々の運転を真似しました。
&gt;&gt; How many miles did you have to drive to train that.
何キロくらい学習のために運転しましたか。
&gt;&gt; Oh thousands of miles.
何千キロも運転したよ！
We spent thousands of miles everyday in the desert.
私たちは毎日何千キロも砂漠を運転しました。
&gt;&gt; Wow. &gt;&gt; And it took quite a while for it to become smart.
(驚嘆) そしてほとんど私の運転と変わらなくなりました。
&gt;&gt; Your poor grad students.
できの悪い卒業生ね。
I can only imagine.
想像しかできないけれど。
&gt;&gt; Well, I was the guy who had the pizza for everybody, but, it was a great time
ピザの配達係みたいだったけど、素晴らしい時間でした。
because it was no email, we just had the, us and the software.
メールに縛られずに、自分とソフトウェアのためだけに時間を使えたし、
And every time you got the software back it was very obvious,
ソフトウェアのフィードバックはどんな時も明快でした。
&gt;&gt; Oh, that sounds great.
楽しそう！
So, I think we should probably get started with that.
というわけで、私たちもここから始めようと思います。
Let's try out a few different supervised classification problems.
いくつかの"supervised classification"問題に取り組みましょう。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so the unit's all about supervised learning, so let's dig in.
そうしましょう。 ここで学ぶことは"supervised lerning"です。お楽しみに。
&gt;&gt; Sounds great.
楽しみ！